

#### Profile

Hardworking and curious electrical engineer with a wide array of experiences. My love for learning, and solving problems and my diverse background in engineering, coding, and management make me versatile in any team. Freelancer - Software Developer Coding, AI/ML, LLM.

## Employment History

Head of the Regional Competence Center for Mechanical Engineering and Mechatronics - Establishment Phase at Technical School Čakovec

March 2022 — November 2023

- Actively engaged in the implementation of two EU projects (EBRD

   European Fund for Regional Development, ESF European Social
   Fund) valued at €7.5 million
- Spearheaded multiple project-based initiatives such as drafting procurement specifications, organization of events, educational visits, partnerships

### Teacher of Electrical Group Subjects at Technical School Čakovec September 2018 — March 2022

- Conducted comprehensive lectures on various topics including microcontrollers, PLCs, embedded systems, automation, robotics, business communication and foundational electrical topics.
- Undertook roles such as Class Master, team leader for Renewable Energy Sources, and Chair of the school's Electrical Engineering Council

# Head of International Projects and Sales Network at ENERGY PLUS

January 2016 — July 2018

- Supported top-tier international clients and presented the company at fairs
- Worked on LED lighting projects documentation and investment projects, emphasizing Energy Performance Contracting

#### Agency Director at Međimurska energetska agencija d.o.o.

January 2013 — January 2016

- Directed agency operations, resource management, growth strategies and successfully transformed the agency's financial standing toward complete self-sustainability.
- Managed multiple energy-focused projects and campaigns, promoting, and implementing energy efficiency and renewable energy adoption

#### **Details**

Croatia

00385992656398

mario.klobucaric@gmail.com

#### Links

Personal Page LinkedIn GitHub

#### **Skills**

Python

Python for Data Science & ML

**VS** Code

Jupyter Notebook

OpenAl API

Git/GitHub

Embedded

Arduino, Raspberry PI

C++

SQL

HTML & CSS

Dart&Flutter

**REST APIs** 

Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

#### Languages

Croatian

English

German

#### **Hobbies**

Reading: Technology, the Future, People, Mindset, Psychology, Personal Growth

#### Licensed Designer at DORS PROJEKT & ZG-PROJEKT

June 2007 — December 2012

- Designed electrical installations for various sectors, including "smart home" and photovoltaic plants.
- Designed electrical installations for highways, tunnels, and road lighting

#### Education

#### Faculty of Organization and Informatics, Varaždin

October 2017 — June 2018

- 56 ECTS
- Specialization: Teacher Education (Pedagogical/Psychological/Didactic/Methodical)

# University Specialist of Strategic Entrepreneurship, 60 ECTS, Faculty of Economics, Zagreb

2009 - 2011

- Thesis: Leadership in Social Responsibility & Social Entrepreneurship
- GPA: 4.6/5

# Graduate Electrical Engineer (Industrial Electronics), 274 ECTS, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing, Zagreb

October 2000 — July 2005

- Thesis: Multichannel Receiver for Surface Electromyography
- GPA: 4.15/5

### Natural Science and Mathematics Gymnasium, Čakovec

1996 — 2000

Awards: 1st (3x) & 3rd (3x) in County Mathematics Competitions (13-18 years)

#### Courses

# Various online courses on topics: Python, Data Science, ML, Flutter and similar, Udemy

2019 - 2023

### **★** Personal projects

2019 - 2023

- Robotic arm system with Python GUI on Raspberry PI.
- Flutter app for OpenAI models: GPT Chat, Whisper, Dall-E.
- ComfortClick-based home automation with integrated security and adaptive heating (KNX & Modbus).
- Raspberry PI web server for environmental data visualization.
- 3D printed foldable drone with betaflight.